Nel Armstrong

Highland Park, NJ | 2136531502 nelhamstrong9@gmail.com

Summary

8 years working as a Software Engineer, focusing on both Front-end and Back-end technologies. Expertise in building and maintaining web applications, CMS, and improving existing systems. Recently launched a location-based app using AI sentiment analysis on App store using program like SwiftUI while utilizing API.

StuntMark is an App that use Sentiment analysis for location based content.

Recent Personal Project

App using AI Sentiment Analysis for location based content, https://apps.apple.com/us/app/stuntmark/id6596733930

Experience

SOLARREVIEWS | NJ, Eatontown SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 01/2022 - 10/2024

- Worked on various projects, improving system functionality, fixing bugs, and ensuring performance optimization.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to enhance system efficiency and user experience.
- Integrated new features and tools, resulting in improved performance and smoother operations.
- Technologies: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Vue, Angular, MySQL.

WARP DEVELOPMENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 03/2017 - 01/2022

- **Trade Cheetah:** Maintained and added new functionalities to an income-trading system, primarily focusing on integrating Highcharts Library for graphical data representation.
- GoldValley: Enhanced the visual and functional aspects of a legacy online gaming system using Vue.js and PHP Laravel.
- **Health Impact:** Developed the front-end of a healthcare web application using Angular, integrating with a .NET Core API for medical event management.
- Aquazania: Built and optimized the responsive e-commerce front end using Angular Bootstrap.

ESP ONLINE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 09/2018 - 03/2021

- Developed a CMS web application and booking engine used by over 200 stores, including the Sorbet chain.
- Collaborated with product managers and engineers to plan and deploy new features, implementing Agile and Scrum methodologies.
- Designed and optimized SQL queries for diverse business requirements, leading to performance improvements.

ISOFLOW

FRONT-END DEVELOPER | 10/2017 - 08/2018

- Created visual elements for web applications, translating UI/UX wireframes into efficient code.
- Developed and optimized web pages using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, improving performance and cross-browser compatibility.

Skills

Javascript, REST, Html5, GIT, AWS, SQL, Software development, Python, CSS, Swift, PHP

Education

UNISA | Cape Town, South Africa BS in Computer Science | 07/2020

Certificates

MCSA: SQL Database Development, 70-761, Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) 98-364 (Database), Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA): 98-361 (Developer)